Johanna Janebäck

Designer and Product owner



Hej!

I am a 28 year old designer and creative from Gothenburg, Sweden, currently looking for new experiences.

What I enjoy most in work and life is getting to be creative and curious, learning new things, and meeting new people. I have always been someone with lots of ideas and plans on how to realize them.

Skills













Fluent in Adobe CS and Figma.

Proficient in Gitlab and CMS Contentful.

Product management, requirements management and elicitation, performance monitoring, UX research and design, web and app development, brand design and marketing.

Brand, digital, product, print and graphic design. Experienced in CAD and 3d-modelling.

Some experience in frontend development and Python programming.

Merits

Finalist Stockholm Water prize, winner of Stockholm Technical Museum's prize for innovation.

Finalist best booth design, IBC Amsterdam 2023 with more than 1250 exhibitors.

Cambridge English: Advanced certificate.

Hobbies

Knitting, ceramics, sports, friends and family.

johanna.janeback@hotmail.com

Education

Chalmers University of Technology, 2020-2022

MSc Interaction Design and Technologies

Chalmers University of Technology, 2017-2020

BSc Design and Product Development

Experience

Satcube AB, 2022 - current employment

Designer and Product Owner

After my first year at Satcube I was promoted to be product owner for our digital services, such as the website, webGUI and app, managing my teams time and prioritizing their tasks in alignment with agile methodology, as well as performance monitoring, product roadmap and quality assurance. I have worked with a wide range of design practices, everything from web and app-design and graphic design to packaging, company merch, event visuals and product design.

UX/UI Designer and Brand Designer

I started and as a UX/UI designer, designing the company website, webgui and app with focus on usability, great looking visuals and brand cohesiveness. I regularly work with our design system and conducting user research.

I have, with management as stakeholders, developed the Satcube brand, logotype, graphic profile and brand book starting with market analysis and a positioning of the company. Currently, I also work closely with the company's marketing team with brand strategy and producing marketing material.

Föreningen Grunden, 2022

Master Thesis

Designing, developing and user testing an event application for people with cognitive disability.

Volvo Cars, 2022

Bachelor Thesis

Designing a flexible pet carrier to suit modern people.

Närhälsan Mölnlycke, 2017-2022

Extra work during my studies

Administrative tasks, mail handling, patient contact and guidance. I worked summers and some winters.

+46 723584967

Göteborg, Sweden